<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://markcheung.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://markcheung.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-02-21T20:10:30+00:00</updated><id>https://markcheung.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Cognitive Science of Good and Bad Habits (WIP)</title><link href="https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2021/Habits/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Cognitive Science of Good and Bad Habits (WIP)"/><published>2021-03-07T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-07T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2021/Habits</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2021/Habits/"><![CDATA[<p>I plan to write a peer-reviewed blog post on the cognitive science for developing habits (and post on sciencenonfiction.org). This is becoming increasingly important due to COVID-19 and the pervasiveness of social media, etc. There are a lot of good resources on this topic, but I hope to offer a more scientific view along with some tips that work for me. Here is just my first draft, consisting of mostly disorganized ideas and resources.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="science">Science</h2> <p>Addiction is essentially bad habits. Science of addiction - dopamine and our reward circuit. Why do we like to be lazy? Short-term pleasures (least effort)&gt; long-term consistency (More effort). Cue -&gt; action -&gt; reward. Action -&gt; routine, wire our reward circuit.</p> <h2 id="tips">Tips</h2> <ol> <li>Start small</li> <li>Be strict</li> <li>Be Consistent</li> <li>Grow</li> </ol> <p>(optional) remove distractions/obstacles (optional) accountability (habit tracker, partner)</p> <h2 id="why-technology-is-not-humane">Why technology is not humane</h2> <p>[I may write in this or another post on how companies profits from our attention and hence wants to keep us addicted and misinformed (misinformation is worth more than information) - quick resoures: Social Dilemma (netflix), Humane Technology]</p> <p>Collective will vs capitalism’s addiction problem https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2020/04/capitalisms-addiction-problem/606769/</p> <h2 id="personal">Personal:</h2> <p>My <a href="/blog/2020/Reflection_week1/">weekly schedule</a> is developed through baby steps.</p> <h2 id="resources">Resources:</h2> <h3 id="books-most-helpful">Books (most helpful)</h3> <ul> <li>Atomic Habits by James Clear - a practical books where some of these ideas are based off of. I included the ones I feel are most important</li> <li>Deep Work by Cal Newport - Examples and reasons for how and why single-pointed focus is producing the best work.</li> <li>(optional) Digital Minimalism by Cal Newport - Tips on minimalizing time wasted on the computer, cellphone, etc. (which some of us struggle with)</li> </ul> <h3 id="appshardware-helpful-at-least-initially">Apps/Hardware (helpful at least initially)</h3> <ul> <li>Freedom - Schedule time for blocking non-essential/distracting websites. Currently, I block them from 10:00pm to 6:00pm M-F (20 hours). Easy to sync across devices.</li> <li>Cold Turkey - Alternative to Freedom</li> <li>Forest - Cellphone App (not using)</li> <li>Kitchen Safe - (not using, but could be helpful)</li> </ul> <h3 id="articles">Articles</h3> <p>https://www.reddit.com/r/nosurf/ https://www.humanetech.com/</p> <h3 id="science-papers">Science Papers</h3> <p>https://link.springer.com/article/10.2165/00023210-200822050-00001 https://www.nature.com/articles/npp2009110 https://psycnet.apa.org/doiLanding?doi=10.1037%2F0022-3514.88.6.918</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="self-development"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[High-level perspective on habits based on science and some of the tips for developing good habits (and geting rid of bad ones).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Advanced Algorithmics and Graph Theory with Python Course Review</title><link href="https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2021/Graph_course_review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advanced Algorithmics and Graph Theory with Python Course Review"/><published>2021-02-07T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-07T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2021/Graph_course_review</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2021/Graph_course_review/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://courses.edx.org/courses/course-v1:IMTx+NET04x+3T2018/course/">Link to course</a></p> <p>Today I finished a short online course on Advanced Algorithmics and Graph Theory with Python. I took this course since 1) I thought it was a good review on graph theory, 2) I knew python, and 3) I had met with one of the instructors at graph signal processing workshop.</p> <p>Overall, I think it is very well organized and easy to follow course. I was familiar with a good amount of the content before taking the course, and found most of the material to be review and at intermediate or beginning levels. The course seems to be helpful as an interview prep for graph-related questions than research. No knowledge of advanced math required.</p> <p>Good:</p> <ul> <li>Easy to follow</li> <li>Recorded + untimed * Untimed (went at my own pace, completed the last 2 modules in 2 days)</li> <li>Short succinct modules (each module takes less than an hour)</li> <li>Separate modules</li> <li>Free to audit</li> <li>Immediate feedback (for quizzes and labs)</li> <li>Since I’m auditing the course, grades are mostly for self-check/motivation.</li> </ul> <p>So far, only slightly annoyance is missing the method signature for A_B in lab 6 (had to debug to find out).</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="self-development"/><category term="AI"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Short online course I have taken.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Entrepreneurship Thoughts</title><link href="https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2021/Entrepreneurship_thoughts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Entrepreneurship Thoughts"/><published>2021-01-03T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-03T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2021/Entrepreneurship_thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2021/Entrepreneurship_thoughts/"><![CDATA[<p>I have been working with 2 CMU students on creating a startup as part of the NSF I-Corps program since early September (which provides some funding for startups). We went through several ideations (brainstorm on ideas) and customer discovery interviews (and switched topic completely).</p> <p>Our first idea was to build a brain-computer interface (BCI) that would allow users to remotely control devices. The BCI should be non-invasive, affordable, and convenient (portable). This is not a new idea, as a lot of recent startups have been working on it (most notably <a href="https://www.next-mind.com/">NextMind</a>). Our value proposition was to focus on everyday situations when our hands + voice control are unavailable. Hence, we named this startup, “Third Hand.”</p> <p>I still think that the idea is great and believe that in the future we would have BCI as a service and perhaps as ubiquitous as cellphones. The main challenge (and reason why we gave up) was the lack of technology and expertise. No one in our team has the experience building a BCI hardware (althought I have experience analyzing brain signals), and we do not want to be dependent on APIs provided by existing BCIs.</p> <p>Still, I learned a lot working on this idea. Here’s a list of what I found most important:</p> <ul> <li>Success of a startup depends highly on the team (working well together is paramount). One of my team members has a lot of experience doing it and actually setup a lot of team building exercises to help us know each other more.</li> <li>Customer discovery needs to be done constantly, especially at the start. We need to first figure out the customers’ problems, and our technology needs to provide the solutions to those problems. We followed a short book called <a href="https://www.talkingtohumans.com/">Talking to Humans</a> that goes more in-depth into the process. It’s very long process that consumed most of our time that we put into this. It is extremely helpful.</li> <li>There are a lot of resources for market research/competitor analysis/value proposition (customer discovery is also very helpful for this).</li> </ul> <p>We are currently working on our 2nd idea (we actually came up with like 20 ideas), social media + map-based travel planner. I think again this is a great idea, but extremely crowded pre-COVID and more difficult now due to COVID-19. I’m optimistic but realistic about this idea. In the worst case, I will learn a lot.</p> <p>I will make a few more posts about our 2nd idea, team, and customer discovery interview results, depending on how they go.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My experience briefly working on the 1st idea of a startup.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LeetCode 1st 50 Coding Problems</title><link href="https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2020/Leetcode_50problems/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LeetCode 1st 50 Coding Problems"/><published>2020-12-06T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-06T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2020/Leetcode_50problems</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2020/Leetcode_50problems/"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img src="/assets/img/leet_code_first50.png" alt="Pie chart showing 50 problems completed" height="90%" width="90%"/></p> <p><em>50 done, 1577 left</em></p> <p>Today (actually a few weeks later) I have completed the 1st 50 problems in Leetcode, (mostly as part of the better habits initiative, i.e., fun things during breaks from deep work). I spent on average, 10 minutes on easy questions, 20 minutes on medium, and 60 minutes (or more) on hard. About half of the problems were straightforward to me. For some of the hard problems, I looked at the hints and solutions if I did not figure them out within 20 minutes (or only figuring out the brute solutions that end up being too slow) and implemented them during another break (without looking at the solutions again). I am thinking about redoing the harder ones. I am also looking into other resources (e.g., Code Forces, Google Kick Start, AtCoder, the Competitive Programmer’s handbook).</p> <p>Some of the problems have very interesting/optimal solutions (in terms with either time/space). I think most of the problems are fun to work out. My favorite is probably the sudoku solver, which is solved via recursion and backtracking. For some problems, I probably didn’t do the way they wanted, i.e., using built-in functions like sorted to find the median of two lists.</p> <p>Below is a list of what I have learned (and remembered):</p> <ul> <li>For dynamic programming, caching results can save a lot of time</li> <li>Dynamic programming can be implemented recursively (top-down) or iteratively (bottom-up)</li> <li>Expression/wildcard matching is just working out of scenarios using conditionals</li> <li>Some very clever ways of solving problems (e.g., rotate image problem has a quick solution, reverse axis, then swap indices. Finding power of a a number recursively by splitting it into two).</li> <li>Not learned here, but a great tip is to implement the brute force solutions before trying to opimize it (sometimes the way to optimize it becomes obvious after doing so, e.g., caching results).</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Completed the 1st 50 coding problems.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Running 10K</title><link href="https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2020/10K_VRC/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running 10K"/><published>2020-11-01T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-01T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2020/10K_VRC</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2020/10K_VRC/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="on-running-10k">On running 10K</h2> <p>Today I ran a 10k (10 kilometers, a quarter of a marathon) sponsored by Vienna Running Club in Virginia. I did not prepare actively and only looked up the recommended schedule for it the day before (which convinced me I shouldn’t try a half-marathon that’s doubled the distance). What I did was essentially 1) making sure I was not tired/injured (by not running for the past 3 days), 2) drinking lots of water the day before, and 3) getting a good night sleep. I had been running up for around 5-6 miles at least weekly at around 9 mins/mile pace prior, so my plan was to just keep moving below that pace for the entire duration as much as possible.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"><img src="/assets/img/10K_2020_10_18_with_VRC.png" alt="10K route and pace" height="90%" width="90%"/></p> <p><em>Route and pace of 10K from Strava</em></p> <p>Generally, I am satisfied with my results. I was with the fast group until around 4 miles when we started going thru hills (which was much more exhausting to me than other runners). I was aware that we sped up after 2 miles (around the turn to Gallows road), but it was easy to keep up as the road was mostly flat. I slowed down a lot around miles 4-5 especially for the hills with steep incline. I plan to work on that along with interval running. I feel tired but happy after the run.</p> <h2 id="on-running-with-others-during-covid-19">On running with others during COVID-19:</h2> <p>I have been running outdoor every Tuesday with the group since early Summer. I think it is relatively safe compared with indoor sports. Otherwise, I wasn’t very motivated to run (instead I walked with my mom almost every other day).</p> <p>I think I need the companionship/peer pressure to push myself to exercise more. I don’t socialize much after the run (due partly to COVID-19, my hearing, laziness, and simram), but just having people working towards the same goal is motivating to my mind, especialy for tasks I generally dislike. I have been working on this during meditation.</p> <h2 id="on-exercise">On Exercise</h2> <p>I will make another post on the exercise routine I’m failing to follow. It is essentially:</p> <ul> <li>running 3x/week</li> <li>bodyweight+core 3x/week (so far I’m only doing this maybe 0.5x/week)</li> <li>yoga 1-2x/week</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[1st 10k I did with Vienna Running Club (probably 1st/2nd ever).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CMU Career Fair</title><link href="https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2020/Career_fair/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CMU Career Fair"/><published>2020-10-04T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-04T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2020/Career_fair</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2020/Career_fair/"><![CDATA[<p>I attended the virtual career fair hosted by CMU from 9/14-9/16. I think the whole process was helpful but inefficient for finding the job, as most recruiters just linked us their sites for dropping our resumes. After spending around 5 hours across 3 days, I was able to have just 5 1-1 chat (either by video/audio/chat) with the recruiters (so it’s 1 recruiter/hour). As a lot of people pointed out, the process would be significantly improve with a built-in queue, limited idle time, wait room (for rooms that are full), etc.</p> <p>I am not sure if I should get some more experience in the industry first before committing to the startup. I think it depends on how my current startup goes (which I will write about in another post).</p> <p>I will go through the process, i.e., get career help from CMU career center, network, apply for jobs, interviews, etc. partly to familiarize myself with the process. And who knows? I might find a job that I like.</p> <p>I have two main criteria for careers: 1) to make enough money to become financially independent so I can spend more time to meditate. 2) to benefit humanity (ideally by helping us understand ourselves better). I will highly prefer to work for a humane tech (headspace, freedom.to, etc.) over techs that profits more from our lower senses / addictive online behaviors (games, videos, etc.).</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My career fair experiences + career aspirations.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 1 Reflection</title><link href="https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2020/Reflection_week1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 1 Reflection"/><published>2020-09-06T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2020/Reflection_week1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2020/Reflection_week1/"><![CDATA[<p>Today marks the end of the 1st week of the Fall Semester, so I feel it is a good time to start a blogging practice.</p> <p>The purpose of this blog is partly for self-improvement and self-reflection, and partly to share what I feel may be helpful to others and myself years ago. I will take entries from my journal and organize and expand them. Some of these posts will be self-help tips from books/articles I read. I plan to also write reviews and reflections on books/articles/my experiences. Everything will be highly subjective and my own opinion and does not reflect anybody else’s.</p> <p>Below is my weekly schedule for the weekdays (with non-weekly events removed). My weekend schedule can be very arbitrary from working on the house/yard trips with family, shopping, etc.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"><img src="/assets/img/weekly_schedule.png" alt="Weekly Schedule" height="80%" width="80%"/></p> <p>I think the major details are as follows: 1) I am planning to focus a lot more on research by scheduling at least 4 hours of <a href="https://blog.doist.com/deep-work/">deep work</a> (for intense projects) with breaks on as many days as possible. Examples of deep work include designing a new architecture, analyzing the theoretical bounds on performance, coding the algorithm, and writing the thesis. In other words, deep work is work that requires some thought.</p> <p>2) I just have two long-term projects that require a bit work (besides research):</p> <ul> <li>contributing to open source projects (started mostly because of jobs): Thursday, Friday, and the weekend</li> <li>blogging (which I’m doing here): mostly during the weekend (but I write everyday during the night daily).</li> </ul> <p>3) I also schedule better habits before 8pm (reading during breaks, playing piano, light coding problems), and more shallow habits at the end of each day during “Play” (youtube, Ted, Twitch, surfing the web, etc.,).</p> <p>4) For exercise, I plan to run on Tuesday and Thursday, and either Saturday and Sunday. On Friday (and potentially Monday), I will practice yoga with at most 1-2 others. On Monday and Wednesday and Saturday, I plan to do a bit bodyweight exercises (with an iPad when I don’t need to pay as much attention)</p> <p>There are a lot of other details that I will leave for another post.</p> <hr/> <p>My first and most important tip is forming a habit to write and reflect everyday starting with at least 2 minutes, preferably near the end of the day. I started this habit by scheduling just 5 minutes of free write before I slept on what I am grateful for and what I feel can be improved. Some days, I spent just 3-4 minutes listing these things. Other days, it ends up being 10 minutes. Since it is short, I have missed only a few days so far.</p> <p>This reflection practice can be incorporated into meditation practice (and I probably will eventually, but now I am still focusing on developing concentration). I will write more on meditation in another post.</p> <p>I think keeping a diary/journal is one of the most efficient ways for self-improvement. As long as we constantly reflect on our actions, we can eventually improve.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reflection on the first week of the semester and general schedule for the rest of the semester.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Neuroscience of Taming the Wandering Mind</title><link href="https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2020/Taming_mind/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Neuroscience of Taming the Wandering Mind"/><published>2020-09-06T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-09-06T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2020/Taming_mind</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://markcheung.github.io/blog/2020/Taming_mind/"><![CDATA[<p>Posted originally at <a href="https://sciencenonfiction.org/2017/09/06/the-neuroscience-of-taming-the-wandering-mind/">ScienceNonfiction Blog</a>, edited and reviewed by <a href="https://www.cmu.edu/student-org/pcr/">Public Communication for Researchers</a>.</p> <hr/> <p>Have you ever tried sitting still and relaxed for three minutes, and focusing on a simple thing? You can focus on a familiar name, a simple image, a small nearby object, or a sensation like breathing. If other thoughts, feelings, or sensations come up, gently ignore them and return your attention to the initial thought.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"><img src="/assets/img/Novice_meditating_in_forest.jpg" alt="Novice Meditating in Forest" height="70%" width="70%"/></p> <p><em>A young monk meditating in the forest (image from <a href="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/9/98">Wikimedia Common</a>)</em></p> <p>How long are you able to focus? How many distractions come up? Kudos if you can hold the thought with no distractions for more than a few seconds. Most of us can’t. Thoughts naturally pop up in our minds, whether we like it or not. If we can slow the stream of thoughts, we can focus better (and hence be more productive). One way to do this is by practicing mindfulness.</p> <p>The <a href="http://www.apa.org/monitor/2012/07-08/ce-corner.aspx">American Psychological Association</a> defines mindfulness as “moment-to-moment awareness of one’s experience without judgment.” There are many mindfulness practices, such as yoga, tai chi, and relaxation therapies. Mindfulness can be promoted by practices like mindfulness meditation. A brief and common example of mindfulness meditation practice is the three-minute exercise described earlier.</p> <p>Many varieties of mindfulness meditation affirm that it is possible to train our minds to become more aware of our thoughts, to tune out distractions, and to become better at focusing both during meditation and in everyday life. Although many claims about the benefits of mindfulness meditation are anecdotal and not yet substantiated, there is scientific basis for some of its benefits. Some of the <a href="http://www.apa.org/monitor/2012/07-08/ce-corner.aspx">empirically supported benefits</a> of mindfulness include stress reduction, cognitive flexibility, and boosts to working memory.</p> <p>To understand how mindfulness meditation works, let’s delve into the basic neuroscience behind brain wandering. While awake and not focusing on the outside world, our brains are constantly in a wandering state. Using a popular brain imaging technique called fMRI, scientists have <a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/nyas.12360/abstract">found</a> that the primary areas of brain activity of this wandering state can be simplistically separated into hubs that are broadly responsible for emotion about ourselves and others, autobiographical memory, and future simulations. Unsurprisingly, we gravitate to those kinds of thoughts when we try not to think. These regions are also associated with anxiety, depression, and addiction.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"><img src="/assets/img/default_mode_network-wrnmmc.jpg" alt="Default Mode Network"/></p> <p><em>A fMRI of the side (left) and the top (right) views of the “wandering” network in human brain. The hubs roughly correspond to areas responsible for emotion, memory, and decision-making. (image from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Default_mode_network">Wikipedia</a>)</em></p> <p>In contrast, during the three-minute mindfulness practice, our brains tend to activate areas that form the “Task-Positive Network” (TPN), which is broadly responsible for directing our focus to both sensation and memory. By activating TPN, we can become more aware of our breathing, conversation, or any other internal and external stimulus. As the TPN becomes more activated, our brains <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1157105/">wander less</a> and become less activated. Essentially, mindfulness meditation leads to increased activity in TPN and decreased activity in the wandering network. For longer-term meditators (years to decades), research shows more profound changes in both brain structure and behavior.</p> <p>One way to test those changes is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Motion-induced_blindness">motion-induced blindness test</a>, in which participants focus at a stationary dot with a moving background, until some or all of the other stationary dots seem to disappear. On average, ordinary people maintain a ‘blindness’ state for around 3 seconds. In a <a href="http://www.nature.com/news/2005/050606/full/news050606-8.html">2005 experiment</a>, Buddhist monks who have practiced meditation for 5 to 54 years maintained this for 4.1 seconds while the most experienced meditator maintained the illusion for more than 12 minutes. This is one of many experiments that showed that meditation practitioners can focus more easily.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"><img src="/assets/img/WLBIB_monk_EEG08_2827.jpg" alt="Buddhist monk with sensor net"/></p> <p><em>A Buddhist monk, Matthieu Ricard, in a meditation pose wearing a sensor net for measuring brain activity. (image from <a href="http://news.wisc.edu/newsphotos/davidson08.html">WISC</a>)</em></p> <p>This all sounds fascinating, but it should be taken with a grain of salt. Research in this area has a lot of challenges, such as reliance on self-reported progress and the placebo effect. A <a href="http://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0153220">review</a> of 124 published trials on mindfulness, and 36 systematic reviews found evidence of reporting bias (e.g., under-reporting undesirable results). A step towards fixing these problems is to use randomized longitudinal studies with large sample sizes. However, there is still consensus in the scientific community that mindfulness meditation can positively change our brains.</p> <p>If you found yourself switching to email or Facebook halfway through this piece, don’t worry – mindfulness is a skill you can learn. Research suggests a mindful mind is often a <a href="https://news.harvard.edu/gazette/story/2010/11/wandering-mind-not-a-happy-mind">happy mind</a>. If you want to get started, try watching one of these <a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/andy_puddicombe_all_it_takes_is_10_mindful_minutes">many</a> <a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/pico_iyer_the_art_of_stillness">TED</a> <a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/amishi_jha_how_to_tame_your_wandering_mind">talks</a> (including <a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/matthieu_ricard_on_the_habits_of_happiness">one given by the monk</a> shown in the above picture) or one of the <a href="https://www.headspace.com/">many</a> <a href="https://www.calm.com/">mindfulness</a> <a href="https://insighttimer.com/">apps</a>. Start small, keep practicing, and in a few years, maybe three minutes of focus will be easy – and you may find yourself more efficient, happier, and perhaps more spiritually fulfilled.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="meditation"/><category term="neuroscience"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The basics of mind-wandering and mindfulness, and how to start meditation.]]></summary></entry></feed>